### LELAND BYRD

Austin, TX

Phone: 214-213-6486 | Email: byrdsjobhunt@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/leland-byrd | GitHub: https://github.com/Byrdbass &

https://github.com/LelandByrd | Portfolio: www.LelandByrd.com

#### SUMMARY

Web-Developer, Software engineer, and Scrum Master with background as a Teacher and an Orchestra Director. Has created multiple apps for Education. Loves leading engineers to success, and has an obsession with problem solving. Enjoys Agile Development to give clients scalable applications with a sleek user experience. Strong public speaker, communicator, and teacher with a Masters in Education. A precise programmer with a love of music.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Typescript, C#, Git, JavaScript, UNIX, python, CSS, HTML, MySQL, noSQL, Frameworks/Applications: React, redux, Jira, DotNet, Spring, AppDynamics, SpringBoot, Linux, CLI, MERN stack, Node, handlebars, Splunk, Hlbernate, Materialize, REST APIs, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, GraphQL, Ableton Live, Audio Engineering

#### **PROJECTS**

### GoalSetter for Teachers | https://st-goalsetter-embed.vercel.app/|

- A chatbot using Open AI, chatbase API and pdf export for teacher goal setting
- Typescript, react-redux, redux-saga, styled-components

### Decked-Out | https://github.com/clabel95/Decked-Out |

- A flashcard style study app for memorizing and learning vocabulary or other skills
- React, MERN stack, graphQL Javascript, CSS, materialize, Adobe Photoshop I

### Ikigai-Bot | https://ikigaibot.vercel.app/

- A chatbot built to help students and young adults find a career path
- Javascript, CSS, HTML, SQL, DotNet, APIs, Typescript

### EXPERIENCE

### Full Stack Developer -

2023 -

## Integral-Ed

Austin, TX / Hybrid

TypeScript, React redux, redux-saga, Vercel, OpenAl API, chatbase API, Airtable, Softr, QuickBooks API, styled-components, Slack Automation, AI generation, Google Workspace Manager, Financial Reporting, Systems Developer

Key Accomplishments:

- Ran platforms as System Administrator and Senior Developer, reviewing Pull requests
- Created System Architecture for Automated workflow for Client Projects
- Worked closely with UX designers, Clients, and Project managers for CI and CD

### Web Developer -

2023

**TrueCoders** 

Birmingham, AL / Remote

React, JavaScript, Node, mySQL, git, CSS, HTML, materialize-css, Tailwind-css, Scrum/sprint planning, Ant-Design, Developed and Deployed resources for Coding Bootcamp and Taught Web Development classes. Led advanced Training in Git and Github. M.C. for graduations.

### Key Accomplishments:

- Developed Curriculum and created a 10% increase in project performance
- Collaborated on Student and Admin Portal with over 10k lines of code
- During first class, Was the first instructor to have had students hired in Web Dev.

### Software Engineer -

2022 - 2023

InfoSys Richardson,TX / Remote

Curriculum Writing for Trainees, Spring Cloud, MicroServices, Consul, Load-Balancing, Service-Discovery, API Gateway, JPA, JDBC, yml, Spring Boot, Maven, Apache, AOP, Dependency Injection, Jenkins, Splunk, Jira, AppDynamics, Postman. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Obtained Certifications in React, Java, SQL, Spring Boot, and Spring MicroServices.
- Led daily Scrum meetings, led sprints for several Full stack java/react applications
- Led a team of engineers through a pilot training project that was implemented Nationally
  - This led to a 50% increase in associates deployability

# Instructional Specialist - Web Development University of Texas - 2U/Trilogy Coding Bootcamp

2021 - 2023

Austin, TX /Remote

Trained a cohort of future Web-Developers and Software Engineers. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Extensive troubleshooting with a variety of issues with Git, terminal applications, Operating Systems on Mac and PC, Program installation, and environment variables.
- Led over 100 non-technical students to a career in Coding.

## Orchestra Director Frisco ISD

2014 - 2021

Frisco, TX / Remote

Led over 100 beginner to advanced musicians from ages 11-14. Grew program by 25% enrollment. Trained fellow orchestra directors in Technology applications and hosted large Performance events. Conducted and facilitated performances on and off campus within a 50 mile radius. Held parent meetings, fundraisers, social events, video presentations, streaming events, and collaborative experiences with other Fine Arts departments. Strong Experience with Virtual Teaching through Zoom.

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Presented tech applications in my first year to a team of 20+ fellow directors.
- Hosted over 1000 musicians on campus for a Solo-Ensemble Events
- Incorporated Electronic music, sound effects, and percussion with String Orchestra
- Taught virtually and in-person at the same time with a custom stream setup

### **EDUCATION**

**Boot Camp Certificate:** University of Texas, Austin, TX

A 12-week full-time intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.is, and ReactJS. Maintained an A+ average on all assignments.

**Masters of Computer Science and Music Education:** Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX

**Bachelors of Computer Sciences and Music Performance:** Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX